<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elite Coaching Blog</title>
    <description>Motivational Coaching</description>
    <link>http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Put Off Procrastination - Tip #3: Avoid Perfectionism</title>
      <description>&lt;div class=&quot;photo-container&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/img/book.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;perfectionism&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Photo by: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.kozzi.com/stock-photo-25138981-bukas-na-aklat.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sergey Nivens&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop being so hard on yourself! Demanding so much from yourself will make you want to stop before you even start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even if you manage to trick yourself into taking action, you will have trouble being happy with what you've created because you can always find something &quot;wrong&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop sabotaging yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not saying you should stop striving for quality in the products or relationships you create or the way you spend your time. That's not the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I'm saying is: &lt;b&gt;Don't ignore the positive things.&lt;/b&gt; If you constantly focus on what's missing, you will never be happy. Your brain will link your goals to pain and before you know it, you will give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, &lt;b&gt;learn to be happy&lt;/b&gt; even if things aren't perfect. Learn to value yourself more. Be proud of your hard work and pat yourself on the back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the results are not there yet, don't worry. Over time, you will get better.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2013 09:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com/put-off-procrastination-tip-3-avoid-perfectionism</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com/put-off-procrastination-tip-3-avoid-perfectionism</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don't Fall For These 3 Planning Mistakes</title>
      <description>&lt;img src=&quot;/img/planning.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;planning&quot; /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Mistake #1: Never being ready&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planning is great. But how much is too much? How can you stop over-planning?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To answer these questions, you need to know what problem you are trying to solve. Why do we plan in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planning provides us with the tactics and confidence. If you are not sure what you should do to make progress, you need to come up with the tactics. If you don't think you're good enough to do something, despite spending a lot of time preparing and working on your skills, you need to work on your confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preparing can go a long way toward helping you become more confident, but achieving high levels of confidence will require that you perform the task. To be good at something, you need to do it. Not just read about it, or plan indefinitely. Start right now, or figure out exactly what you need to do before you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Mistake #2: Planning too far ahead&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much can you really predict? Not that much, really. So plan accordingly. You may feel confident about the things in the near future. Focus on your next move. You can try anticipating what might happen in the near future, but don't expect your plan to handle every possible variation years from now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan is not the end goal. There is no guarantee of success. Don't be shortsighted. If you execute the plan perfectly, you did a great job following the plan, but don't be surprised if the results don't reflect your efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Mistake #3: Making no adjustments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reality changes. The only constant thing in the world is change. What might be a good idea now, might not be a good idea later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And not just that. Reality is different from how we experience it. We all have our own &quot;reality&quot; and in our heads, a plan might work out perfectly, but the truth is, you won't know until you go ahead and do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iterate! Make a reasonable plan and execute it. Then reflect on what worked and what didn't and adjust the sails accordingly. The success might come sooner than you think.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com/dont-fall-for-these-3-planning-mistakes</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com/dont-fall-for-these-3-planning-mistakes</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Put Off Procrastination - Tip #2: Prioritize Better</title>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/qZDNFtKvdWo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Procrastination can't be avoided. You can only do a limited number of things at any given moment, and the rest will need to be postponed. Of course, choosing the tasks that are more important than others can be a challenge. It is very important to make this choice consciously, and not just go with the flow. Be aware of this choice and you will make better decisions already.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all of us share the same values, so we can't come up with a list of values that will work for everybody, but I do invite you to make this list for yourself. You need to get clear on what matters to you and not get caught up in the details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another thing that I want you to perfect is to recognize the difference between urgent and important. Many people don't differentiate the two, or say they do but don't apply it. Every item on your todo list should be marked as urgent, important, both urgent and important or neither urgent nor important. Obviously, the tasks that are both urgent and important need to be worked on first, and tasks that are neither need to be worked on last. The tasks that are important, but not urgent, usually take precedence over tasks that are just urgent. The reason why is because if the task is not important, then the urgency is just a distraction that appears important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I'd like you to do today is look at your todo list (or create one if you don't have it written down) and mark each task as urgent and/or important. You can use letters U and I right next to the task description. Then sort the list according to the rules we talked about: both urgent and important go first, followed by just important, then we have just urgent and finally, neither urgent nor important. This is the order in which you should start working on your tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 05:12:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com/put-off-procrastination-tip-2</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com/put-off-procrastination-tip-2</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Put Off Procrastination - Tip #1: 15 Minutes</title>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/GqcT66wOe4I&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Procrastination is frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It stands between you and your goals like a brick wall. You need to climb over it, but there are no immediate rewards on the other side, just more work. To make things even worse, the more you worry about it, the less energy you have left for climbing. You know you need to get to the other side, but your brain is telling you that it might be too difficult, and you don't even try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sounds familiar?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't worry, a lot of people feel the same way. Today I will share one simple, but very effective tip on dealing with procrastination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the challenge:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get yourself to start! Identify one task that you've been putting off, and work on it for 15 minutes. Do it right now if you can. Otherwise, schedule a 15 minute block in your calendar. If after 15 minutes, you feel like you want to continue working, great! If not, take a moment to realize that you resisted the temptation to procrastinate and that you've gotten closer to your goal, so celebrate!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here's the reason why this simple technique works: When we procrastinate, we tend to exaggerate the pain we'll endure while doing the activity, and understate the pain of not doing the activity. 15 minutes seems easy enough to do (which translates to less pain), and it makes you feel good about making progress on your goal (and you experience more pleasure).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So take action right now, and share in the comments what it is that you are trying to do. Let's support each other and beat procrastination once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 12:50:52 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com/put-off-procrastination-tip-1</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com/put-off-procrastination-tip-1</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Life Coaching</title>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/yiAFFIZQRM8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've received a lot of questions about my life coaching business: what it is and how does it work and why did I decide to do it so I decided to make a video about it because I believe that my story will empower and inspire you to open the door to the opportunity that is present in your own life that you may have been putting off. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is life coaching? Life coaching is an activity during which a coach helps clients identify personal goals and design an effective strategy to reach them. In life we constantly make decisions. Even if you don't do anything, you are still making a decision not to take action. The quality of our life is directly proportional to the quality of our decisions. That's why it's very important to consciously recognize your opportunities and align them with your needs and wants. But what is it that prevents us from achieving our goals? The most common obstacle is fear, the force that pulls us back and prevents us from taking action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life coaching process provides you with the tools and techniques to overcome fear, and break through your limiting beliefs and get that life you deserve. Applying life coaching principles can transform your life. In my sessions I go even a step further and teach you these principles so you can apply them yourself in the future. We all know the saying &quot;Give a man a fish and you feed him for a day. Teach him how to fish and you feed him for a lifetime&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've spent many years of my life studying the fields of personal development and psychology. I started because I wanted to better understand myself and the world around me. My insatiable desire to improve myself accelerated my personal growth, and I was in the state of immense happiness. But then I realized that to remain happy one needs to keep growing, and if you constrain the growth to yourself, sooner or later you will realize that to get past that point, you need to give back. I didn't conceive it until later, when I became aware of how much I have been helping the people in my environment, my friends, without ever asking for anything in return. Seeing them change their states from feeling sad, depressed and confused to being determined, happy and in control of their own lives was the greatest gift I could ever get. And one day I realized how much meaning I find in the things I have been doing and how most people need someone to prevent them from letting their limiting beliefs slowly erode and eventually destroy their dreams. We don't do this consciously, we just get caught up in everyday life, ignoring the inner voice that's telling us what it is that we really want and refuse to admit to others or worse yet ourselves that we are ready for a change. I deeply believe that we all have capacity for making this change happen. The question is not &quot;Can you&quot;, but &quot;will you&quot;. The only way out is through, so stop making excuses. Acknowledge your own needs and don't be afraid of overcoming your fears! My own life coach opened my eyes when she showed me how much passion and drive was locked up inside of me and how much energy was wasted on the inner conflicts I used to have. Once I resolved them, I felt so powerful that I felt that the fears I was having had to give way to the new me, the true me. And this incredible feeling of integrity challenged me to make this change in others. And that lead me to a career in life coaching.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 09:50:52 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com/what-is-life-coaching</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com/what-is-life-coaching</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seeking Approval From Others</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you constantly seeking approval from others? Watch this video to find out why you should avoid approval seeking behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/sEWvdGbBMoU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2012 10:11:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com/seeking-approval-from-others</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com/seeking-approval-from-others</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get to Know Your Personality Better With Enneagram</title>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/xdY118tFMiw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2012 10:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com/enneagram</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com/enneagram</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Makes Us Do Things We Do</title>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/AFboHBGZ880&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 09:24:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com/what-makes-us-do-things-we-do</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com/what-makes-us-do-things-we-do</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pomodoro Technique Explained</title>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/OtvcxCf2q_4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 13:50:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com/pomodoro-technique-explained</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elitepersonalcoaching.com/pomodoro-technique-explained</guid>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
