<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elite Coaching Blog</title>
    <description>Motivational Coaching</description>
    <link>http://www.elitecoaching.us</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.elitecoaching.us/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Characteristics of Well Functioning Teams</title>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/3xuJWKrSM0o&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.elitecoaching.us/ten-characteristics-of-well-functioning-teams</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elitecoaching.us/ten-characteristics-of-well-functioning-teams</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Develop Skills Faster</title>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/PdS8k8LbrIY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 15:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.elitecoaching.us/how-to-develop-skills-faster</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elitecoaching.us/how-to-develop-skills-faster</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Become a Leader</title>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/i_XPBPrYoec&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 17:15:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.elitecoaching.us/how-to-become-a-leader</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elitecoaching.us/how-to-become-a-leader</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Overcome Procrastination by Prioritizing Properly</title>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/auE5ufFDHuE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2014 17:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.elitecoaching.us/how-to-overcome-procrastination-by-prioritizing-properly</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elitecoaching.us/how-to-overcome-procrastination-by-prioritizing-properly</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Make And Manage Changes</title>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;360&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/im0eII24Bdc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 05:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.elitecoaching.us/how-to-make-and-manage-changes</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elitecoaching.us/how-to-make-and-manage-changes</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Master Any Skill</title>
      <description>&lt;div class=&quot;photo-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://www.elitecoaching.us/img/toastmasters.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;toastmasters&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm a Toastmasters member. For those that don't know, Toasmasters is a club whose purpose is improving your public speaking skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When making any type of decision, as part of the process, we commonly identify the return on investment. We evaluate the benefits, risks and investments to see if the commitment is worth the prize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mastering public speaking has many benefits. Public speaking develops your ability to communicate things clearly and concisely, not just when speaking to a group of people, but also in a one-on-one conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also improves your self-confidence. The Toastmasters club is a friendly and supportive environment, but still, before every speech, you get nervous. You start doubting yourself. &quot;What if I mess up and embarass myself?&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially Table Topics. If you don't know how Table Topics work, this can be a little shocking to you: You are supposed to give a short speech without any preparation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scary, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Table Topic Master gives you a topic and after that you have only a few seconds to think about it before you start speaking. Sometimes you are familiar with the topic and you have thought (or maybe even talked) about it before. But other times, you need to do all the thinking in those few seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that knowing what to talk about is not all there is to it. You need to think about how you are going to express yourself, while observing the audience and taking their non-verbal feedback into account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This teaches you to focus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, to be able to deliver an impromptu speech succesfully, realize that nervousness can be converted to positive energy. This approach builds your confidence and self esteem. It gets easier every time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's also very interesting is that when doing a table topic for the first time, a lot of people do a great job, but when talking to them afterwards, they think they sucked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, be proud of yourself for overcoming the fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most important lessons you learn at Toastmasters is how to deal with fear. The fear loses its power when you realize that you speak in public all the time anyway. You talk to people at work, your family and your friends, and you don't fret over what you're going to say next or what's going to happen if you say something stupid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In concluding this blog post, I'd like to ask you to realize that you may apply this strategy to the areas other than public speaking, as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Find a low risk environment and commit to practicing the skill on a consistent basis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Prepare the best you can, and find excitement in the things you can't predict&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Learn from other people's feedback and self-reflection &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now pick a skill you would want to master and give it a try. Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 14:15:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.elitecoaching.us/how-to-master-any-skill</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elitecoaching.us/how-to-master-any-skill</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We Are All Under Pressure</title>
      <description>&lt;div class=&quot;photo-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://www.elitecoaching.us/img/pressure.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pressure&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Photo by: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kozzi.com/stock-photo-25231958-businesswoman-carrying-cube.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sergey Nivens&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A single woman with no kids in her late 20s who is constantly asked &quot;Have you met anybody?&quot; or &quot;When are you going to have kids?&quot; is under a lot of pressure. So is a man who worked hard to save up enough money and now wants to take a risk of quitting his day job and starting his own company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Family and friends are well intentioned. They want you to be happy. But the problem is that their expectations might not match yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people offer advice based on their values, not yours. Instead of trying to understand you and support you, they want to tell you what they would do if they were in your situation, ignoring your individual needs and beliefs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This lack of perspective on their side makes the existing process of going through a change (or not wanting to go through a change) more difficult and painful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So how do you deal with it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Get clear on what you want and stick with it. Believe in yourself. Be patient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Surround yourself with supportive people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Don't worry too much about people who don't get you. If they truly care about you, they will respect your decisions regardless, since all they really want to see at the end of the day, is you being happy.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2013 15:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.elitecoaching.us/we-are-all-under-pressure</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elitecoaching.us/we-are-all-under-pressure</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pain Is a Teacher</title>
      <description>&lt;div class=&quot;photo-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://www.elitecoaching.us/img/disappointment.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;disappointment&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Photo by: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kozzi.com/stock-photo-25272452-people-in-love-shot-in-studio.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ship Factory&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You feel pain for a reason: Your body is letting you know that something needs to be changed. It makes you aware of a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often times, the pain teaches you a lesson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you try to avoid pain, you may &lt;strong&gt;never learn the lesson&lt;/strong&gt;. I'm not talking just about physical pain. Emotional pain can be avoided as well, by distracting yourself or using drugs or alcohol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes people &lt;strong&gt;learn the wrong lesson&lt;/strong&gt;. I tore the ACL in my right knee playing basketball - maybe I should've never played? If a woman gets cheated on, are all men unfaithful? If you are not happy with your past, should you give up on your future?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pain can &lt;strong&gt;make you a better person&lt;/strong&gt;. You may know some great people who experienced a lot of pain in their lives. It is much easier for you to understand how another person feels if you've felt that way before. Be careful, though, every situation is different - don't assume too much too early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The saying goes: &quot;If it doesn't kill you, it makes you stronger.&quot; If you've experienced a tremendeous amount of pain in the past, the present and future might look less scary, because the new pain will be insignificant in comparison to the old pain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The alternative is to get scared of the additional pain or start feeling &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Learned_helplessness&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;helpless&lt;/a&gt;. You decide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pain can be a very strong &lt;strong&gt;driving force&lt;/strong&gt;. Have you ever said to yourself (or heard someone else say) in frustration: &quot;I've had enough!&quot; At that point, the pain reached the level at which it can't be tolerated anymore. The point at which frustration and anger become a promise to yourself that the pain of taking action can not be nearly as bad as the pain of the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 16:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.elitecoaching.us/pain-is-a-teacher</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elitecoaching.us/pain-is-a-teacher</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Run a Company Like Jason Fried</title>
      <description>&lt;div class=&quot;photo-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://www.elitecoaching.us/img/business-success.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;business success&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Photo by: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kozzi.com/stock-photo-25019825-business-success.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sergey Nivens&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I went to see &lt;strong&gt;Jason Fried&lt;/strong&gt;, the co-founder of 37 Signals, give a talk about their ideology and reasons for their success. Here are some things he shared:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be patient.&lt;/strong&gt; We see companies like Facebook, Twitter or Instagram achieve overnight success (or what looks like overnight success), and believe that is the norm, while in reality, those companies are lottery winners. Most companies grow at a much slower rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do not raise money.&lt;/strong&gt; Bootstrap. This will teach you how to &lt;strong&gt;make&lt;/strong&gt; money, instead of how to &lt;strong&gt;spend&lt;/strong&gt; money. Furthermore, you will have the freedom to make decisions and control the timeline without the pressure from investors who want their money back quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on the long term.&lt;/strong&gt; The companies that stay in business for a long time are automatically successful. They survived, which means they found something that works. After being in the industry for such a long time, their experience helps them make better decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What will you customers or clients want in &lt;strong&gt;10 years&lt;/strong&gt;, but &lt;strong&gt;also want it now&lt;/strong&gt;? Amazon customers won't ever say: &quot;I wish that shipping took longer or was more expensive.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on what matters&lt;/strong&gt;, and focus on it now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hire remote workers.&lt;/strong&gt; In some industries, this may not be possible, but in software development, there is no reason for a company to miss on the best talent available just because they aren't in the 30 mile radius. Similarly, the employee should be able to live wherever he or she wants and work for a company of choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Marketing is not a department.&lt;/strong&gt; Marketing is everything you do. At 37 Signals, marketing is everybody's responsibility. Every blog post and tweet is obviously marketing, as well as every communication with a client and the product that you create.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Culture is not what you &lt;strong&gt;say&lt;/strong&gt; you do, but what you end up &lt;strong&gt;doing&lt;/strong&gt;. It is not what &lt;strong&gt;should&lt;/strong&gt; be, but what &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evaluate people based on the &lt;strong&gt;value&lt;/strong&gt; they produce, and not by how many &lt;strong&gt;hours&lt;/strong&gt; they put in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to motivate employees is to give them work they find &lt;strong&gt;meaningful&lt;/strong&gt;. This will motivate them intrinsically and make them productive and loyal. Somebody else can always give them more money or offer better perks, so don't rely on these extrinsic motivational factors (but do pay above market rates).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have an idea you would like to work on, &lt;strong&gt;do it&lt;/strong&gt;! Start small and see how it goes.&lt;br /&gt;
A few hours a week may be enough. That way, you can give your project a shot, but if it doesn't work out, it won't be too big of a deal.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 13:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.elitecoaching.us/how-to-run-a-company-like-jason-fried</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elitecoaching.us/how-to-run-a-company-like-jason-fried</guid>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have Strong Enough Whys</title>
      <description>&lt;div class=&quot;photo-container&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://www.elitecoaching.us/img/little-girl-thinking.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;thinking&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Photo by: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kozzi.com/stock-photo-25034597-little-girl-thinking.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Robert Byron&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you feel like you need to do something, or that you &lt;strong&gt;should&lt;/strong&gt; do something, but don't really &lt;strong&gt;want&lt;/strong&gt; to, there is a conflict inside of you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One part of you thinks it's best for you to go ahead and do the task, but another part resists that thought, and wants to do something else (or nothing at all).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be honest with yourself. Why do you think you should do it? What happens if you don't? Free yourself up from this obligation and convince yourself that &lt;strong&gt;you have a choice&lt;/strong&gt;. If you don't do anything, will the world come to an end? If you don't take action, what's going to happen tomorrow? What about a week later? A month later? Year, 5 years? Will the pain grow in intensity, or will it vanish? What will happen to the reason you are doing this in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now let's switch things a little. What if you do take action? What pain will you endure? How long will this pain last? Is this pain long lasting, or is it just temporary? What is it exactly that's stopping you from taking action?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep asking yourself why, and drill deeper and deeper with each question. Get to the bottom of this. &lt;strong&gt;Tell yourself the truth, no matter what.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2013 16:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <link>http://www.elitecoaching.us/have-strong-enough-whys</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elitecoaching.us/have-strong-enough-whys</guid>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
